[♪ opening theme song playing]
♪
Hold on. What's this?
That's Tanikaze.
How did they get here?
[Tsugai 1
and Tsugai 2 yelling]
[BUNBUN] Everybody...
-[all gasp]
-...get down!
[Midori grunts]
[rumbling]
[Hagure whimpers]
Another one? What is happening?
What's that?
[Midori sighs]
[Tachikawa whimpering]
[JIJIMARU] My!
That's one sturdy sack.
[MIDORI] Mm-mm-mm!
-What's going on?
-[BABAMARU] Tanikaze exploded.
[Natsuki grunts]
Akio! Bunbun!
-[TSUGAI 1] One, two...
-[TSUGAI 2] Three, four...
Akio isn't down here.
He's gone?
[SAKURAZAWA]
Well, he didn't blow up.
His viscera would be
all over the walls.
So he escaped?
[SAKURAZAWA] Aw, man.
Looks like I'm gonna need
a whole new infirmary.
[JIJIMARU] We've been had.
Daemons always prioritize
their master's safety.
They took advantage of that.
Uh? Wait, so because
I was in danger,
Midori had to let go of Akio?
[NATSUKI]
Midori did nothing wrong.
He protected you,
just like he should.
Show him love. He's a good boy.
-[Midori moans]
-[Tachikawa chuckles]
I saw something on it
before it blew.
There was a slimy mold
growing on Tanikaze.
Earlier, I saw the same stuff
on Yamakaze at the front gate.
[Natsuki exhales]
[BUNBUN] I think
it's some kind of parasite
that makes its host explode.
But I wasn't able to detect
the daemon responsible for it.
So it isn't just mold.
That must be only one part
of the daemon.
[JIJIMARU]
It can split into pieces?
So it's like Asuma's daemons.
In that case,
when did they get infected?
I don't know. Damn it all.
Who'd do something like this?
Turning helpless relics
into suicide bombers.
They're monsters.
All right. Come on.
We're finding Akio.
[BABAMARU AND JIJIMARU]
Mm. Mm.
Look over there! Pair off!
Daemons are inclined to protect
their masters above all else,
and they used that.
[servant grunting]
[NATSUKI]
I don't deny that's true.
And yet,
did they do it to free him,
or did they want Akio dead?
♪
[ASA] Tell me
your honest thoughts!
Do you like
this picture or this one?
Personally, I think
they both look great!
[FEMALE DAEMON]
We're back from patrol!
[ASA] Doggie!
[MALE DAEMON] There were a few
police cars at the warehouse,
but nothing major.
It didn't seem like
anyone was freaking out.
Yeah?
The sword pervert slaughtered
a whole bunch of people,
but no one's taken notice.
Guess they have someone
to get rid of the bodies, too.
Seems so.
Jin's daemons are much the same.
He had called them "janitors."
Jin? Oh. So you've
usually got him
when things get too messy.
I haven't seen his daemons yet.
Guess I'd better be careful.
I wouldn't wanna be next.
Yes, indeed.
Of course we have a cleaner.
Any self-respecting
faction would.
Say, for example,
Higashi Village's "gravedigger."
[DERA] This old goat.
How much shit
does he have on Hana?
-[door opens]
-Hmm?
I found their security room
and erased all their footage.
Tell me, Tadera.
How are your driving skills?
Decent enough.
[ASUMA] That car belongs to me.
You may use it to get back home.
[DERA] Uh?
Hey, thanks for the ride.
So did you bug this thing?
Gonna tail me again?
Certainly not.
In fact, I'd like to apologize
for the other day.
Jin was quite angry with me.
Trust it will not happen again.
[DERA] Yeah, totally.
Before Tadera gets away,
is there any info
you can get off of him?
I'm afraid not.
He doesn't have
his own daemons with him,
so there's nothing we can do.
-[GONZO] Mm...
-[phone rings]
[GONZO] Jin, son. I'm so sorry.
I meant to come right back...
What?
The infirmary?
Is Dr. Sakurazawa okay?
-I see. Find him.
-[call disconnects]
Asuma, Asa, time for us to go.
-It seems Akio escaped.
-[Asuma gasps]
[both gasp]
[Yuru grunts]
He... got away?
-[Right and Left grunt]
-[YURU] Him too?
And just like that,
our only lead
on Mom and Dad disappeared.
-[Yuru grunting]
-What's going on?
-Yuru! What's wrong?
-[DANJI (TSUGAI)] Yuru!
-[Yuru breathes heavily]
-[DERA] Whoa, there!
You okay, kid?
He's running a fever.
This isn't uncommon
after people leave the mountain
for the first time.
It's like a new world to them,
with new viruses
and new bacteria.
If that weren't enough,
he's barely had a break.
He's been fighting nonstop
since we got here,
leaving him constantly tense.
His body must be
screaming at him.
Let's get him to our infirmary.
Can't. It is out of commission
right now.
Just hold on. You'll be okay.
Leave it to me.
I've seen this before.
Your brother's gonna be fine.
We just gotta lay low
for a bit at my pad.
I'll contact you again
through Jin's bar.
Just wait till then.
♪
[phone chimes]
[Akai moans]
[Asa sighs]
That said, being betrayed
by someone this close
really stings.
[Asa chuckles]
[Haruo exhales]
[NATSUKI]
We need to expand our search.
We'll send one team to the back
and another one to the annex.
-[SERVANT] Master Jin!
-Uh?
[NATSUKI]
Did you two have any luck?
There's nothing to find.
His room's a bust.
Listen up. If you locate Akio,
don't engage.
Just alert us
as fast as you can.
[ALL] Sir.
He should be considered
an extremely dangerous target.
As a rule, stay in groups
of two or more.
No matter what,
don't ever find yourself alone.
[servant grunting]
-[servant choking]
-[Tsugai growling]
[AKIO] Sorry, little guys.
You're strays now.
Well, I'm sure you'll be found
before long.
Uh?
♪
[sighs]
[HANA]
It's not bleeding anymore.
All we do is wait for the skin
to heal on its own.
Did he ever get a tetanus shot?
Every kid in Higashi did.
The late shaman
took care of that.
I fixed up an ice pack
if you want one.
[HANA] Thanks, Ken.
[Yuru grunts]
[HANA] Now you need to get
some shut eye.
It's not too cold
on your neck, right?
No, it's good.
Sorry for the trouble.
When you're this sick,
you shouldn't be worried
about any dumb crap like that.
We've all gotta help our friends
when they're in need.
Those aliens...
or rather, the daemons
in black had said that.
"We're all the same.
None of us can live alone."
[Yuru groans]
Thank you, Ken.
The next time you're sick,
I'll hunt a boar and cook up
some stew just for you.
[KEN] Mm...
Please keep your care-giving
within the bounds of the law!
Should we be in fear
for his life?
With us by his side,
he should make it
through this A-okay.
I'm sorry for worrying you.
I'll be fine.
[Ken grunts]
Now what do you think
you're apologizing for, lad?
Just rest and get better!
Then our hunt for the pervert
may continue!
[Yuru groans, chuckles]
Your hand's cool.
The soft stone feels nice.
[RIGHT] Uh?
-Oh, really?
-'Tis only logical.
[RIGHT] Very well!
Take these to fight your fever!
-[thuds]
-[Yuru groans]
I think I'll pass, actually.
[HANA] Some sleep
will be good for you.
Night-night.
And with that out of the way,
I don't even know
where I'm supposed to start
with the rest of you guys.
Another secret love child?
She's just a child
from Higashi Village
who was kidnapped.
[HANA] You can't have
an actual dog in here.
The building doesn't allow pets.
[DERA] He's a Daemon Wielder.
[BOTH] This perfect specimen...
is our beloved master!
[HANA] Leave Earth in peace.
You're Zashiki-Warashi, right?
Legends say you bring
good fortune to homes.
Please enjoy your stay.
May I give you a seat?
[BOTH] Double-standard!
[Oshirasama, in sing-song voice]
I'm back!
It seems we found
quite the party!
[both exclaim]
Your small apartment
is turning into a real clubhouse
for daemons.
Not to suggest
we don't want you to join us,
but didn't you go home?
[Oshirasama chuckles]
We went sightseeing in Tokyo!
Looks like you had
a real fun time.
[OSHIRASAMA] I did,
and I got enough souvenirs
for everyone.
[HANA] Hold on, you have
human money on you?
Wait. Did you make yourself
visible to shop?
[OSHIRASAMA]
We just talked to seers.
Temples and shrines
are full of them!
Our new friends gave us
lots of knickknacks!
Oh, my! You're new here.
You must be little Danji's
other half!
This is Oshirasama.
Good evening.
[OSHIRASAMA] And this one...
Is she a girl from the village?
Oh, what a sweetheart!
I simply love children!
Oh, right, she can't see us.
[AZAMI] Uh?
Hi there.
-I'm Oshirasama!
-[Azami groans]
[DERA] Uh-oh!
She's goin' down again!
Here. Would you take care
of this for me?
[Azami gasps softly]
Thank you, miss.
[BOTH] She won her over!
[cries] So, uh, some scary guys
attacked the village.
The bad people killed my mommy.
It was awful.
Oh! That must have been hard.
You're so brave, dear.
Whoa! She got the kid
to open up in no time at all.
There was a girl.
And even though
she had cute braids
and a red outfit,
her face looked mean.
She moved her hands,
and the adults split in half.
And that's how Mommy...
Would this be the girl
with the denture daemons
you mentioned a while ago?
Yep. Some pipsqueak named Gabby
and her chompy friends.
The way Asa was talking,
it seems like the Kagemoris
take good care of her.
But they still killed
Azami's ma.
We can't just force her
to stay with them.
Though if she goes back,
Higashi might
throw her in a cell
because she's seen too much!
No way!
Please, will you keep Azami
safe here?
[Hana stutters] Aw, what?
Why is it every time
you leave the house,
you come back with a new kid
we need to take care of?
I mean, it kind of makes sense.
Won't she feel better in a place
with people she knows,
like Yuru and me?
[HANA] And how
do you think we can afford
a whole another child?
Or did you forget,
you might never get any work
from Higashi Village again
after your little falling out
with the bandits the other day.
I wonder when
the next G-one race happens.
-[chuckles]
-[Hana grunts]
You are not gambling
our money away!
It's not gambling if I win.
It'll happen this time,
I promise.
[Azami cries]
[KIRI (TSUGAI)] It'll be okay.
[DANJI (TSUGAI)]
We're here for you.
I want to go home.
[OSHIRASAMA]
On the bullet train?
Or on the highway? Horseback?
[Azami continues crying]
[overlapping chatter]
[MALE DAEMON] You can do it.
[indistinct chatter]
[KEN] A sick person's
trying to sleep.
Keep it down.
This just confirms what I knew.
I'm the only normal one here.
I'm so sorry.
How are you supposed
to get any rest like this?
[gasps]
What? Where'd Yuru go?
How could he have left
if he's too sick to walk?
He hasn't strayed too far, lad.
[YURU] I'm in here.
[screams]
What are you doing
stuffed inside your closet?
Get your little butt back to bed
this instant.
No, thanks. I'm comfortable.
Small, dark places
help me feel relaxed
when I'm too sick to fight.
What are you, a wild animal?
Quite the opposite of Asa.
[HANA] So, what do you think?
-Are you well enough to eat?
-[Yuru groans]
-[HANA] How about some rice?
-Yes, please.
All right. [chuckles]
That's the stuff.
I don't know how you do it,
but these are amazing!
Aw, you flatter me.
When you're done with those,
try taking these.
[YURU] Huh?
What are these pebbles?
[DERA] Analgesic antipyretics.
Mm. If I'm already
not feeling well,
why would I eat
some strange little rocks?
[DERA] You'll be fine.
The people up in the village
take these all the time.
It's the medicinal painkiller
I used to bring you guys
from the outside world.
I ground them up
so they'd look kind of special,
but you can buy them
at any corner store.
[YURU]
The medicine's that common?
[DERA] Yep, these things
are mass-produced
-by some machines.
-Uh, in the village,
people would talk about this
like it's a miracle cure.
I figured it was
a luxury product
made by some master healer.
[chuckles] It gets the job done.
[YURU] Umm...
♪
[Yuru breathes shakily]
[Yuru grunts]
[DERA] I told you
to finish eating
before you took it.
But hey, at least
your appetite's back
with a vengeance.
-[HANA] Hmm.
-[Yuru grunting]
[KEN] Uh?
[Right chuckles]
[OSHIRASAMA] Isn't this
a beautiful view, darling?
[horse neighs]
[HANA] Of course,
right as my husband's income
is about to tank,
I somehow get stuck
with another little brat.
To make matters worse,
two of our kids
aren't even registered.
What a pain in the frigging ass.
Eh, we'll figure it out somehow.
I don't get how
you're so chill about this.
Where does all that
composure come from?
What? Like it's hard
staying cool as a king
when I know a queen like you
has my back
-no matter what happens?
-[sighs]
So, queen.
You team "Yuru should die?"
It's no secret
I don't like kids.
But I am firmly on team
"adults who trample
over the lives of innocent kids
should die."
[Dera chuckles]
♪
Whew-ie! We've had
a productive day, kiddos!
Time to wash up
and say goodnight.
If you share a room with Yuru,
you might catch
whatever bug he's got.
How about you crash with me
tonight, Ken?
Sounds good.
You'll be staying with me
in my room, Azami.
[AZAMI] Uh? [groans]
This young lady's
gonna take care of you!
She's not scary, I promise.
♪
[Hana breathes deeply]
[snores, chuckles]
[Dera snoring]
[Ken and Azami whimpering]
[BOTH] This room is terrifying.
-[footsteps]
-[siren wailing distantly]
-[MINASE] Oh, there you are.
-[Akio grunts]
I've been waiting, Akio.
[exclaims]
-Hey, Mom, you're here.
-[Minase gasps]
-What happened to you?
-I'm okay.
No, you're clearly not okay!
And you're pale as a ghost!
I lost a little blood.
I think I need some rest.
Forgive me, son.
I should have come
to save you myself.
I never would have let
something so awful
happen to my baby.
[AKIO] Thank you, Mom.
[MINASE] But now,
I'm never letting you go.
Never, Akio.
[AKIO] Hm.
♪
[MISASAGI]
The ties of one's blood
are nothing but a curse.
No matter how hard
we might try to fight it,
we can't escape that truth.
Got some context there?
[MISASAGI]
We've recovered Akio alive.
Recovered! Recovered! Recovered!
I'm impressed!
I thought he was dead meat.
My apologies. I guess
I missed him with my blast.
Bah! I'm sure we can find
some way we can use him.
Now then, I wonder how much
of our information
leaked to Jin's guys.
With a little luck,
the Kagemoris
and Higashi Village
will keep tearing each other
limb from limb.
I hope so.
Ivan even managed to kill
a bunch of
Higashi Village fighters.
Limb from limb!
Limb from limb! Limb from limb!
[BUNBUN] Oh, I just remembered.
A while back,
I think I heard about a mold.
There was a story
from my homeland.
You're not from around here?
[BUNBUN] My ancestors were
from Tottori prefecture.
If I'm remembering
the story correctly,
there's a daemon
from Western Japan
that attaches to relics.
And they sprout
some kind of slime-mold.
-[both grunt]
-[BUNBUN] It's gotta be.
I did see it. It was that daemon
from out West.
It's been 400 long years.
We can't miss our opportunity
to set matters right.
And this war
will belong to the West.
♪
[♪ closing theme song playing]
[ASA] He was a normal man
who didn't wish death
on anybody.
He was just trying
to live his life!
[YURU] Do you want me
to go with you
and teach 'em all a lesson?